three.com.au 2014-11-30

# About - Legal - Privacy Policy - Vodafone Australia

Protecting your privacy is a big deal, so we’re strict about how we handle your personal information. This privacy policy outlines how we collect, store, use and disclose any personal information you provide us.

This privacy policy also confirms Vodafone’s obligations under the Privacy Act 1988 (“Privacy Act”) and the Telecommunications Act 1997. 

### What is your personal information?

In this privacy policy, the term ‘personal information’ has the meaning given to it in the Privacy Act. It can include your name, address, telephone number, email address and profession or occupation. If information we collect personally identifies you, or you are reasonably identifiable from it, the information will be considered personal information.

### Why do we collect personal information?

To provide you with mobile services and products (including your phone and broadband), we need to collect some of your personal details. Without this, we’re not allowed by law to provide you with the products and services you want. 

### What personal information do we collect?

  * The information we collect about you depends on the Vodafone products and services you use and subscribe to. It may include:
  * your name, date of birth and contact details including your physical address, email address and telephone number;
  * your bank account and credit card details;
  * information to verify your identity such as your driver’s licence number (or other approved government ID);
  * information relating to your credit worthiness;
  * your employment history, if you apply for a job with us; 
  * details of products and services we’ve supplied you or you’ve enquired about, as well as any additional information needed to deliver those products and services or respond to your enquiries;
  * your preferences for particular products, services or lifestyle activities when you tell us what they are, or you preferences based on how you use our products and services;
  * the websites you visit and the online searches you perform;
  * information about your account (including your password and username) and your use of mobile voice and data services; 
  * any additional information relating to you that you provide to us directly  through our websites or indirectly through use of our websites or online presence;
  * your employment-related information if you apply for a position with us; and
  * information you provide to us through customer surveys.

### We may also collect information about how you use our products and services such as:

  * the phone numbers that you call or send messages to (or the phone numbers that you receive calls and messages from);
  * the date, time and length of the calls and messages you send or receive through our network, and your general location at the time these calls and messages take place;
  * the level of service you receive (eg. network faults and other network events which may affect our network services); and
  * the date, time and length of your internet browsing, and your general location at the time.

### How do we collect personal information?

  * We collect your personal information in a number of different situations, including when you: 
  * provide information to us in account application forms, service enquiry forms, or when you purchase products or services from our website;
  * subscribe to newsletters, alerts or other services from us;
  * take part in a competition, prize draw or survey;
  * visit our website, online store, Facebook page and other pages that we own and manage; 
  * visit external websites and perform online searches using your Vodafone device;
  * visit external pages through our portals like Vodafone Live;
  * make calls to Vodafone. These calls may be recorded for training, quality and business purposes; 
  * use your mobile device;
  * use your mobile device and this results in interactions between your mobile device and our network and other equipment. These interactions might tell us something about you, your mobile device and your usage of our services (including location-based information);
  * apply for a position with us.

### We collect personal information about you from other sources including:

  * other companies in the Vodafone group
  * credit reporting agencies, law enforcement agencies and other government entities; 
  * entities that provide services to us, including the entities to which we may disclose your personal information.  See below for information about those entities and publicly available sources of information, like market research providers. 

We might also collect information by other means and will take all reasonable steps to inform you if and when we do.

### How do we use cookies?

We might also use cookies (small text files stored in your browser) and other techniques such as web beacons (small, clear picture files used to follow your movements on our website). These collect information that helps us understand how you use our online products and services and how we can make them more relevant to you. 

We may use a persistent cookie (a cookie that stays linked to your browser) to record your visits so we can recognise you if you visit our website again. It also lets us to keep track of products or services you view so that, with your consent, we can send you news about them. 

We also use cookies to measure traffic patterns, to determine which areas of our website have been visited and to measure transaction patterns in the aggregate. This helps us research our users’ habits so that we can improve our online products and services. You can set your browser so your computer refuses cookies or lets you know each time a website tries to set a cookie.

We may log IP addresses (that is, the electronic addresses of computers connected to the internet) to analyse trends, administer the website, track user movements, and gather broad demographic information.

### How do we use your personal information?

  * The personal information we collect may be used for a number of purposes including:
  * providing you with mobile phone and broadband products and services. This might include extra services not in your agreement with us and services that use information about where you are when using your mobile device (location information); 
  * contacting you with messages about changes to our products or services;
  * generating bills, managing your account, and carrying out debt-recovery functions;
  * processing orders or applications to become a customer;
  * verifying your identity;
  * carrying out credit checks and credit reporting;
  * dealing with enquiries, complaints and other customer care activities;
  * carrying out market analysis and research, development of our products and services, and to understand how customers use our network, products and services on an anonymous or personal basis;
  * analysing the services, products and other things that interest you, and the locations in which you use your mobile device, in order to provide you with services, products and information suited to your needs, interests and location; 
  * contacting you about our products and services and those offered under other brands that our group owns, which may include marketing these products to you.  See below for more information about direct marketing communications;
  * identifying your location so we can send you emergency alerts;
  * protecting our network and managing the volume of calls, TXTs and other use of our network. For example, we identify peak periods of use so our network can better handle the volume at those times;
  * conducting internal investigations in relation to crime and fraud prevention, detection, recovery or prosecution; and
  * training our staff.

For other purposes, Vodafone will ask for your consent to use your personal information.

### Direct marketing communications

  * We may send you direct marketing communications and information about:
  * our products, services, discounts, competitions and special promotions that we consider may be of interest to you;
  * offers or promotions based on how you use our products and services. These include your calling and messaging activities, location information and browsing information;
  * other companies' products and services (including offers and discounts we’ve specially negotiated for our customers) we think may interest you, if you’ve chosen to receive this information.  

These communications may be sent in various forms, including by telephone, post, fax and any form of electronic message (including email, SMS, MMS, PXT or Video PXT).  

You consent to us sending you those direct marketing communications by any of those methods.  If you indicate a preference for a method of communication, we will try to use that method whenever practical to do so.  

In addition, at any time you may opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by contacting us (see the details below) or by using any opt-out facilities provided in the marketing communications and we’ll make sure your name is taken off our mailing list. 

We may give your personal information to other organisations for the purposes of direct marketing.  However, these organisations are limited to our dealers and sales agents working directly on behalf of Vodafone. Otherwise, you can separately opt-in to receiving third-party marketing through a specific promotion.

### How can you opt-out of marketing materials?

If you’d rather not get our direct marketing communications, it’s easy to opt-out. Just go to this link: <http://support.vodafone.com.au/articles/FAQ/How-to-stop-Vodafone-marketing-material>

or contact **1555** from your Vodafone mobile or call **1300 650 410** from any phone. You can also use any opt-out methods provided in our marketing communications, and we'll do the rest. 

Just a heads up that we’ll still need to send you essential information about your account, changes to your service or plan and other information required by law.

### Who can we provide your personal information to?

Vodafone might disclose your personal information both within and outside Australia to:

  * credit providers or credit reporting agencies for the purposes permitted under the Privacy Act and credit reporting legislation;
  * our service and content providers including the providers of IT services and mailing services; 
  * our dealers, agents, contractors and advisers;
  * our mobile device manufacturers and repairers;
  * our providers of marketing, research, call centre and telemarketing services;
  * Vodafone Hutchison Australia and other companies in the Vodafone group;
  * your authorised representatives or legal advisors;
  * our professional advisors including lawyers, accountants, tax advisors and auditors;
  * debt collection agencies and other parties that assist with debt-recovery functions;
  * law enforcement bodies to assist in their functions, courts of law or as otherwise required or authorised by law;
  * emergency services (if you make an emergency call) or other service providers assisting in emergency situations (such as bushfires);
  * regulatory or government bodies to resolve customer complaints or disputes both internally and externally, or to comply with any investigation by one of those bodies; and
  * other telecommunications services providers for the purposes of both unwelcome calls and mobile number portability issues.

We are required by law to disclose certain personal information about you (including your name, physical address, telephone number and email address) to the operator of the Integrated Public Number Database (IPND). Personal information in the IPND is used to assist emergency services and safeguard national security. If you consent, information from the IPND may also be published in public directories or used by directory assistance. IPND information may also be used for research with approval by the ACMA.

### Do we disclose your personal information outside Australia?

Vodafone may disclose personal information to other companies in the Vodafone group as well as third party suppliers and service providers located overseas for some of the purposes listed above.

 We take reasonable steps to make sure the overseas recipients of your personal information do not breach the privacy obligations relating to your personal information.

We may store or sometimes disclose personal information to entities outside Australia, including the following:

  * Companies in the Vodafone group located in the UK and Hong Kong; and
  * Vodafone’s data hosting and other IT service providers located in India, Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, Sweden, the UK and the USA.

### What security measures do we use to protect your personal information? 

The security of your personal information is a high priority for us. We take all reasonable steps to securely store your personal information so it’s protected from unauthorised use, access, modification or disclosure. This includes both physical and electronic security measures.

### How can you protect your account from unauthorised access?

Anyone who knows your account PIN or online username and password can access your account. You must keep your PIN, username and password secure and only share these details with people you authorise to access and manage your Vodafone account. Vodafone accepts no responsibility for information it discloses to parties who know your PIN, username or password.

### How accurate is the personal information we hold about you?

We take all reasonable measures to make sure the personal information we hold is accurate, complete and up to date. However, the accuracy of your information is largely dependent on what you provide us. To make sure we’ve got your most current and accurate details, please let us know when your information changes (e.g. if you change your name or move house). 

### Can you access and correct the personal information we hold about you?

Yes, but there may be instances where we cannot grant you access to the personal information we hold. For example, we may not grant access to information if it could interfere with the privacy of others or if it would result in a breach of confidentiality. If that happens, we will give you written reasons for any refusal. 

To request your personal information simply click the link below, complete the form, and return it to the address provided. We won’t charge you for simply making the request and will not charge for making any corrections to your personal information. We may charge reasonable costs for actioning your request.

If you think your personal information may be inaccurate, incomplete or out of date, you can ask that it be updated. We will update the information by amendment. If we do not agree that there are grounds to amend it, we’ll add a note to the personal information stating that you disagree. 

### How can you report a breach of your privacy?

If you believe your privacy has been compromised, please fill in the Privacy Breach form below and return it to the address provided. A member of our Privacy team will get in touch within 10 business days.

### Contact us

If you have any other questions about your privacy, feel free to call Customer Care on **1555** from your Vodafone mobile, call **1300 650 410** from any phone, or fax us on **1300 308 869**.

Our postal address is:  
**Vodafone Customer Care PO Box 2580    
Kingston Delivery Centre   
Kingston, Tasmania 7050**

You can also contact us online via:

  * Our website: [vodafone.com.au](http://www.vodafone.com.au/)
  * Our blog at [blog.vodafone.com.au/blog/](http://blog.vodafone.com.au/blog/)
  * Facebook at [facebook.com/vodafoneau](http://www.facebook.com/vodafoneau)
  * Twitter at [twitter.com/VodafoneAU_help](https://twitter.com/VodafoneAU_help)

### **Vodafone Privacy Policy, March 2014**

Vodafone Hutchison Australia Pty Limited ABN 76 096 304 620 Vodafone Australia Limited ABN 86 056 161 043 Vodafone Pty Limited ABN 76 062 954 554 Vodafone Network Pty Limited ABN 31 081 918 461 Registered address: Level 7, 40 Mount Street, North Sydney NSW 2060. References to ‘Vodafone Group’ may include Vodafone Hutchison Australia and its parent and related companies.
